Guide to the Morris Edward Opler papers, [ca. 1960-1996]
Opler, Morris Edward papers, [ca. 1960-1996]
- Series I: Apache Indian Tribe
  - Subseries B: Chiricahua
    - Chiricahua Biography (Charlie Smith) (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Chiricahua Biography (Charlie Smith) (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Chiricahua Biography (Charlie Smith) (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Chiricahua Relationships (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Chiricahua and Mescalero Vocabulary (A-Z) (English-Apache) (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Chiricahua Vocabulary I (by subject categories) (English-Chiricahua) (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Chiricahua Vocabulary II (by subject categories) (English-Chiricahua) (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Dan Nicholas' Autobiography-typescript (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - Dan Nicholas' Autobiography (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Sam Kenoi's Autobiography Part I (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Sam Kenoi's Autobiography Part I (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Sam Kenoi's Autobiography Part II (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Sam Kenoi's Autobiography Part II (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Sam Kenoi's Autobiography Part III (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Sam Kenoi's Autobiography Part III (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Sam Kenoi Materials (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Sam Kenoi Materials, 1932 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Sam Kenoi Materials (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Ruth Boyer's Autobiography of a Chiricahua Woman, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Settlement pattern, camp craft, communication (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Customs and etiquette (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Dancing, games, recreation (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - Death, ghost, owl (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Dress and ornamentation (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - Economic life (divions of labor, property, inheritance, hunting) (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - Goodwin (Greenville) Diary of Search for Sierra Madre Appache (Box 36, Folder 18)
    - Goodwin (Neil) Diary of Journey to New Mexico (Box 36, Folder 19)
    - Health, medicine, sickness (Box 36, Folder 20)
    - Historical Material-Fort Sill (Box 36, Folder 21)
    - Historical Material-Fort Sill (Box 36, Folder 22)
    - Historical Material-Prisoners of War and Fort Sill (Box 36, Folder 23)
    - Fort Sill Records (Box 36, Folder 24)
    - Historical material related to removal and imprisonment (Box 36, Folder 25)
    - Data on alleged Chiricahua in Mexico (Box 36, Folder 26)
    - Houser, Allan (Apache Sculptor 1914-1994) (Box 36, Folder 27)
    - Television Project, 1982-1983 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - 70th Centennial, 1983-1986 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - 100th Anniversary of Removal from the West, 1986 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Life Cycle (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Myths and Tales (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Myths and Tales (other field workers) (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Negative Items (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous Photographs (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Photographs of Artifacts (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Photographs of People (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Photographs of artifacts (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Photographs taken by John Green (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Photographs taken by Morris Opler, Harry Hoijer or Thomas Miles (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - Photographs taken from the Heye Museum (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence from the Heye Museum, 1940 (Box 37, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence related to photographs, 1939-1947 (Box 37, Folder 17)
    - Photographs (Box 37, Folder 18)
    - M.E.O. Rose Photographs (Box 37, Folder 19)
    - Oklahoma University Western History Collection (Box 37, Folder 20)
    - "The Apache Resistance"-A Goodwin Film (Box 37, Folder 21)
    - "The Apache Resistance" (Box 37, Folder 22)
    - Plants and Foods (Box 37, Folder 23)
    - Religion, 1983 (Box 37, Folder 24)
    - Religion-Dreams and muscular tremors (Box 37, Folder 25)
    - Religon (Gahe) (Box 37, Folder 26)
    - Girl's puberty ceremony and spring haircutting (Box 37, Folder 27)
    - Religion (Box 37, Folder 28)
    - Paints, rocks, minerals, shells (Box 37, Folder 29)
    - Social Organizations-courtship, marriage, divorce (Box 37, Folder 30)
    - Social Organizations-Blood relatives and affinal relatives (Box 37, Folder 31)
    - Social Organizations-leadership, chieftainship, status (Box 37, Folder 32)
    - Songs (Box 37, Folder 33)
    - Time, calendar, seasons, heavenly bodies (Box 37, Folder 34)
    - War (Box 37, Folder 35)
    - American Indian Institute University of Oklahoma-Indian Oral History Material (Box 37, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence and Oral History Manuscript: "Sam Hauzous, Fort Sill Apache" (Box 37, Folder 37)
    - Lekson, Stephen's materials (Box 37, Folder 38)
    - Field notebooks (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Field notebooks (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Field notebooks (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Field notebooks (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Field notebooks (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Field notebooks (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Chiricahua Apache Film (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Chiricahua Apache Pilgrimage film (Box 48)
  - Subseries C: Mescalero
    - Acculturation (Box 37, Folder 39)
    - Alien People (Box 37, Folder 40)
    - Antelope, badger, bat (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Bear (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Beaver, buffalo (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Cattle, chameleon, chipmunk (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Coyote (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Deer (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Dog (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Elk, fish, fox, frog (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Gila monster, gopher, ground squirrel (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Horse, burro, mule (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Lizard, lynx (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Mink, mountain goat, mountain lion, mountain sheep (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Mouse, muskrat, otter (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Peccary, porcupine, prairie dog (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - Rabbit, raccoon, rat (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - Skunk, snake, squirrel (Box 38, Folder 16)
    - Toad, turtle (Box 38, Folder 17)
    - Weasel, wildcat, wolf (Box 38, Folder 18)
    - Bands and Place Names (Box 38, Folder 19)
    - Biography (Box 38, Folder 20)
    - Blackbirds, bluebirds, buntings (Box 38, Folder 21)
    - Birds (creeper-duck) (Box 38, Folder 22)
    - Birds (bird-tit-cowbird) (Box 38, Folder 23)
    - Birds (eagle-goose) (Box 38, Folder 24)
    - Birds (Grackle-Hummingbirds) (Box 38, Folder 25)
    - Birds (Jays-Lark) (Box 38, Folder 26)
    - Birds (magpie-osprey) (Box 38, Folder 27)
    - Birds (owl) (Box 38, Folder 28)
    - Birds (parakeet-whippoorwill) (Box 38, Folder 29)
    - Birds (prairie chicken-snipe) (Box 38, Folder 30)
    - Birds (sparrows-turkey) (Box 38, Folder 31)
    - Birds (verdin-yellow throat) (Box 38, Folder 32)
    - Childhood and child training (Box 38, Folder 33)
    - Crime (Box 38, Folder 34)
    - Customs and Etiquette (Box 38, Folder 35)
    - Dances (Box 38, Folder 36)
    - Death (Box 38, Folder 37)
    - Designs, Photographs (Box 38, Folder 38)
    - Dreams (Box 38, Folder 39)
    - Dress and decorations (Box 38, Folder 40)
    - Economic life (Box 38, Folder 41)
    - Economic Life (artifacts) (Box 38, Folder 42)
    - Folk Beliefs (Box 38, Folder 43)
    - Food Preparation and Taboos (Box 38, Folder 44)
    - Games (Box 38, Folder 45)
    - History (Box 38, Folder 46)
    - History (Box 38, Folder 47)
    - Hunting (Box 38, Folder 48)
    - Insects (Box 38, Folder 49)
    - Medicine, disease, insanity (Box 38, Folder 50)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 38, Folder 51)
    - Instruments (Box 38, Folder 52)
    - Power Stories I (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Power Stories II (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Power Stories III (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Power Stories Notes (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous Power Stories Cards (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Myths and Tales pages 252-419 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Myths and Tales pages 420-642 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Myths and Tales pages 643-803 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Footnotes I (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Footnotes II (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Footnotes III (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Footnotes IV, V and VI (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous Myths and Tales (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Regina Flannery-Coyote (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - Regina Flannery-Other than coyote (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - Names (Box 39, Folder 16)
    - U. of Arizona special collection photographs taken from the Blazer collection-mostly Mescalero, one or two of Jicarilla when stationed at Mescalero (Box 39, Folder 17)
    - John Gillin Photographs (Box 39, Folder 18)
    - Mescalero photographs (Box 39, Folder 19)
    - Mescalero photographs (Box 39, Folder 20)
    - Mescalero photographs and miscellaneous documentation (Box 39, Folder 21)
    - Mescalero photographs and documentation (Box 39, Folder 22)
    - Plants (Box 39, Folder 23)
    - Plants (Box 39, Folder 24)
    - Plants (Box 39, Folder 25)
    - Mescalero and Chiricahua plants (Box 39, Folder 26)
    - Mescalero and Chiricahua plants (Box 39, Folder 27)
    - Plants (Box 39, Folder 28)
    - Plants (1-40) (Box 39, Folder 29)
    - Plants (41-80) (Box 39, Folder 30)
    - Plants (81-120) (Box 39, Folder 31)
    - Plants (121-160) (Box 39, Folder 32)
    - Plants (161-200) (Box 39, Folder 33)
    - Plants (201-240) (Box 39, Folder 34)
    - Plants (241-280) (Box 39, Folder 35)
    - Plants (281-320) (Box 39, Folder 36)
    - Plants (321-360) (Box 39, Folder 37)
    - Plants (361-371) (Box 39, Folder 38)
    - Religion (crisis ceremonies (Box 39, Folder 39)
    - Religion (Gahe) (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Religion (girl's puberty rite) (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Religion (lightning and thunder) (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Religion (love magic) (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Religion (miscellaneous) (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Religion (muscular tremor and ceremony for indigestion) (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Religion (natural phenomena) (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Religion (peyote) (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Religion (power) (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Religion (shaman and witches) (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Religion (supernaturals) (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - Religion (sweet bathing) (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Religion (war complex) (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - Religion (water, water beings) (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - Rocks, shells, paint, beads (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Sex life (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - Social Organization (Box 40, Folder 17)
    - Social Organization (Box 40, Folder 18)
    - Social Organization (Box 40, Folder 19)
    - Social Organization (Box 40, Folder 20)
    - Time, calendar, seasons, etc. (Box 40, Folder 21)
    - Tobacco, smoking, pipe (Box 40, Folder 22)
    - War (Box 40, Folder 23)
    - War (Box 40, Folder 24)
    - Weapons (Box 40, Folder 25)
    - Acculturation (Box 40, Folder 26)
    - Acculturation (Box 40, Folder 27)
    - Acculturation (Box 40, Folder 28)
    - Sam Chino Records 1-10 (Box 40, Folder 29)
    - Sam Chino Records 11-20 (Box 40, Folder 30)
    - Sam Chino Records 21-30 (Box 40, Folder 31)
    - Sam Chino Records 31-40 (Box 40, Folder 32)
    - Sam Chino Records 41-50 (Box 40, Folder 33)
    - Sam Chino Records 51-60 (Box 40, Folder 34)
    - Sam Chino Records 61-70 (Box 40, Folder 35)
    - Sam Chino Records 71-80 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Sam Chino Records 81-87 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Songs (first draft) (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Songs (first draft) (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Song materials from Paul Frank and Jules Blumensohn (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Hearing on May 13, 1950 in Mescalero, New Mexico (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - New Mexico trip June 28-July 7, 1980 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - C. Weston's Chiricahua film (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Subseries D: Jicarilla
    - Social Organizations (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Centennial, 1982-1987 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - M.E. Opler and L. Balsam report on conditions at Jicarilla Apache reservation (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - Veronica Tiller Balsam Report (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - Agriculture, corn (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - Alien people and their influence (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - Animals and Hunting (A-E) (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - Animals and Hunting (F-Z) (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - Bands and place names (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - Bands and place names (Box 41, Folder 18)
    - Birds (Box 41, Folder 19)
    - Birds (Box 41, Folder 20)
    - Childhood and child training (Box 41, Folder 21)
    - Childhood and child training (Box 41, Folder 22)
    - Childhood and youth in Jicarilla society (Box 41, Folder 23)
    - Crime and Punishment (Box 41, Folder 24)
    - Custom and Etiquette (Box 41, Folder 25)
    - Dances and songs (Box 41, Folder 26)
    - Death, burial, afterworld (Box 41, Folder 27)
    - Dreams (Box 41, Folder 28)
    - Dress and decoration (Box 41, Folder 29)
    - Dwellings (Box 41, Folder 30)
    - Economic Life (A-G) (Box 41, Folder 31)
    - Economic Life (H-Z) (Box 41, Folder 32)
    - Folk beliefs (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Food and drinks (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Food and drinks (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Games (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Hunting (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Insects (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Personal correspondence (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Personal correspondence (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Modern Period (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Muscular tremor and diagnostic signs (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Musical instruments (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Myths and tales (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - Myths and tales (Blue Jay Cycle pages 1-201) (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - Myth and tales (Blue Jay Cycle pages 202-352) (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - Myths and tales (Blue Jay Cycles pages 353-519) (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - Myths and tales (Hactcin and story telling) (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - Myths and tales (War tales) (Box 42, Folder 17)
    - Myths and tales (Harry Hoijer-Text I) (Box 42, Folder 18)
    - Myths and tales (Harry Hoijer-Text II) (Box 42, Folder 19)
    - Myths and tales (Harry Hoijer-Text III) (Box 42, Folder 20)
    - Myths and tales (Harry Hoijer-Text IV) (Box 42, Folder 21)
    - Myths and tales (Harry Hoijer-Text V) (Box 42, Folder 22)
    - Myths and tales (Harry Hoijer-translations) (Box 42, Folder 23)
    - Myths and tales (Father Berard Haile-Text) (Box 42, Folder 24)
    - Myths and tales (Father Berard) (Box 42, Folder 25)
    - Myths and Tales (Father Berard) (Box 42, Folder 26)
    - Names (Box 42, Folder 27)
    - Photographs (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Photographs (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Drawings and pictures (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Plants (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Plants (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Plants and their uses (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Plants and their uses (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Plants and their uses (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Religion (holiness rite) (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Religion (September 15th Ceremony) (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Religion (girl's puberty rite) (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Religion (Shamanism) (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - Religion (Shamanism) (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - Religion (Shrines, etc.) (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - Religion (witchcraft) (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - Rocks, paints, minerals, etc. (Box 43, Folder 16)
    - Sickness, etc. (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - Smoking and tobacco (Box 43, Folder 18)
    - Social Organization (Box 43, Folder 19)
    - Social Organization (Blood relatives) (Box 43, Folder 20)
    - Social Organization (Box 43, Folder 21)
    - Social Organization (Blood relatives) (Box 43, Folder 22)
    - Social Organization (Blood relatives and affinal relatives) (Box 43, Folder 23)
    - Social Organization (Blood relatives) (Box 43, Folder 24)
    - Social Organization (Marriage Arrangements) (Box 43, Folder 25)
    - Social Organization (Marriage) (Box 43, Folder 26)
    - Social Organization (Itsa) (Box 43, Folder 27)
    - Social Organization (Marriage) (Box 43, Folder 28)
    - Social Organization (Marriage) (Box 43, Folder 29)
    - Social Organization (Sex Life: Courtship and love magic) (Box 43, Folder 30)
    - Social Organization (Sex life, pregnancy, childbirth, twining) (Box 43, Folder 31)
    - Social Organization (Sex Life: Abnormal behavior and venereal disease) (Box 43, Folder 32)
    - Social Organization (tribal endogamy) (Box 43, Folder 33)
    - Time, months, seasons (Box 43, Folder 34)
    - War and raid (Box 43, Folder 35)
    - Weapons (Box 43, Folder 36)
    - Woodlore and campcraft (Box 43, Folder 37)
    - Field notebooks (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Field notebooks (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Field notebooks (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - Field notebooks (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - Field notebooks (Box 47, Folder 13)
    - Field notebooks (Box 47, Folder 14)
    - Field notebooks (Box 47, Folder 15)
    - Field notebooks (Box 47, Folder 16)
    - Field notebooks (Box 47, Folder 17)
    - Field notebooks (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - Field notebooks (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - Field notebooks (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - Field notebooks (Box 48, Folder 14)
    - Field notebooks (Box 48, Folder 15)
    - Field notebooks (Box 48, Folder 16)
    - Field notebooks (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Field notebooks (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Subseries E: Lipan
    - History (Dobyns-Microfilm) (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - History (Historical Notes prepared for AAA paper and handbook article) (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Themes (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Birds (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Artifacts (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Childhood and Child Training (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Dwellings (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Animals and Hunting (A-G) (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Animals and Hunting (H-Z) (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Alien People (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - Food (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Games (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - Horse and Pets (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - Insects (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - Localities and place names (Box 44, Folder 15)
    - Medicine and diseases (Box 44, Folder 16)
    - Plants (Box 44, Folder 17)
    - Social Organization (Box 44, Folder 18)
    - Social Organization (Box 44, Folder 19)
    - Death and stories of the dead (Box 44, Folder 20)
    - Folk beliefs and dreams (Box 44, Folder 21)
    - Peyote (Box 44, Folder 22)
    - Religion (Box 44, Folder 23)
    - Games (stave, hoophole) (Box 44, Folder 24)
    - Warpath and raid (Box 44, Folder 25)
    - Weapons (Box 44, Folder 26)
    - Dress and decoration (Box 44, Folder 27)
    - Photographs (Box 44, Folder 28)
    - Social Organization (status) (Box 44, Folder 29)
    - Sun, moon, stars, earth (Box 44, Folder 30)
    - Rocks, paints, minerals, shells (Box 44, Folder 31)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 44, Folder 32)
    - Custom and etiquette (Box 44, Folder 33)
    - Biography (Box 44, Folder 34)
    - Names (Box 44, Folder 35)
    - Musical Instruments (Box 44, Folder 36)
    - Myths and Tales (Box 44, Folder 37)
    - Medicinal Plants (Box 44, Folder 38)
    - Campcraft (Box 44, Folder 39)
    - Population data (Box 44, Folder 40)
    - Anthropological Theory-lecture (Box 44, Folder 41)
    - Apache Kinship outline sheets (Box 44, Folder 42)
    - M.E.O. article on Lipan for handbook (Box 44, Folder 43)
    - Hoijer (Lipan texts) (Box 44, Folder 44)
    - Used Material (Box 44, Folder 45)
    - Article/correspondence (Box 44, Folder 46)
    - MEO article on Lipan for handbook (Box 44, Folder 47)
    - MEO articles and books (Box 44, Folder 48)
    - "The Lipan and Mescalero Apache in Texas", October, 1970 (Box 44)
    - "The Lipan and Mescalero Apache in Texas" draft copy (Box 44, Folder 49)
    - Lipan site near Corpus Christi (Box 44, Folder 50)
    - Lipan ethnography (Box 44, Folder 51)
    - Lipan ethnography (Box 44, Folder 52)
    - Lipan vocabulary and notes (Box 44, Folder 53)
    - Lipan history including bands (Box 44, Folder 54)
    - Lipan history (work of others) (Box 44, Folder 55)
    - History (Dobyns-Progress report) (Box 44, Folder 56)
    - History (Dobyns-microfilm) (Box 44, Folder 57)
    - Lipan-Mescalero Case: Digest List (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - Dobyns' Lipan Research (Lipan Bibliography) I (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - Dobyns' Lipan Research (Lipan Bibliography) II (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - Lipan-Mescalero Location Cards (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - Lipan-Mescalero Date Cards (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - Dobyns' Lipan Research (Lipan Chronology) (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - Dobyns' Lipan Research (Lipan Chronology) cont'd (Box 92, Folder 1)
    - Dobyns' Lipan Research (Persons in Contact with Lipan) (Box 92, Folder 2)
    - Dobyns' Lipan Research (Lipan- General) cont'd (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - Dobyns' Lipan Research (100-103) incl. Place Names/Areas, Provinces, Rivers, Towns (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - Dobyns' Lipan Research (103 cont'd) (Box 94, Folder 2)
    - Dobyns' Lipan Research (110-128) incl. Bibliography (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - Dobyns' Lipan Research (130-178) incl. Geography, History, etc. (Box 95, Folder 2)
    - Dobyns' Lipan Research (180-349) (Box 96, Folder 1)
    - Dobyns' Lipan Research (350-558) (Box 96, Folder 2)
    - Dobyns' Lipan Research (560-648) incl. International Relations (Box 97, Folder 1)
    - Dobyns' Lipan Research (648 cont'd, A) incl. International Relations (Box 97, Folder 2)
    - Dobyns' Lipan Research (648 cont'd, B) incl. International Relations (Box 98, Folder 1)
    - Dobyns' Lipan Research (648 cont'd, C) incl. International Relations (Box 98, Folder 2)
    - Dobyns' Lipan Research (650-888) (Box 99, Folder 1)
  - Subseries F: Western Apache
    - Greenville Goodwin among Western Apache-manuscript (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Acculturation (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with Goodwin (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with Goodwin (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Religion - Silas John. Contains list of images found in folder 10. (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Religion - Silas John (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Religion-Silas John cult Correspondence (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Jules Henry report (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - 4 Day Holy Ground Meeting, 1955 List of images in this folder is found in folder 6. (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Silas John Cult-photographs, etc. (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - Silas John notes (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - Goodwin Field Notes (alien people) (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - Goodwin Field Notes (biographies) (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - Goodwin Field Notes (biographies) (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - Goodwin Field Notes (clans) (Box 45, Folder 16)
    - Goodwin Field Notes (economic life) (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - Goodwin Field Notes (miscellaneous) (Box 45, Folder 18)
    - Goodwin Field Notes (religion) (Box 45, Folder 19)
    - Goodwin Field Notes (religion) (Box 45, Folder 20)
    - Goodwin Field Notes (religion) (Box 45, Folder 21)
    - Goodwin Field Notes (religion) (Box 45, Folder 22)
    - Goodwin Field Notes (war) (Box 45, Folder 23)
    - Photographs (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Photographs (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Article for handbook (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Subseries G: Kiowa
    - Oklahoma Project (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Article for handbook (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Material on William E. Bittle (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Material on William E. Bittle (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Brant material (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Photographs (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Brant material (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - Apachean Seminar (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous notes, correspondence and journal articles (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous notes, correspondence and journal articles (Box 46, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous notes, correspondence and journal articles (Box 46, Folder 15)
    - Photographs (Box 46, Folder 16)
    - Goddard manuscripts-correspondence, 1955-1968 (Box 46, Folder 17)
    - Goddard manuscripts-Mescalero (Gotal) (Box 46, Folder 18)
    - Goddard manuscripts-Mescalero (texts) (Box 46, Folder 19)
    - Goddard manuscripts-Mescalero (Box 46, Folder 20)
    - Goddard manuscripts-Lipan (Box 46, Folder 21)
    - Apache Claims Cases-correspondence, 1950-1965 (Box 46, Folder 28)
    - Chiricahua Claims Case-miscellaneous (Box 46, Folder 29)
    - Mescalero Claims Case-Findings (Weissbrodt) (Box 46, Folder 30)
    - Mescalero Claims Case-Findings (Weissbrodt) (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Western Apache Claims Case-Digest (Box 47, Folder 2)